An important aspect of DNS to understand
both for the exam and beyond is the concept
of different types of resources
records and what they do in DNS.
Here we’ll cover some of the more popular
types of resource records starting with the
most common type of record an A record. A
records resolve host names to IP addresses,
specifically IPv4 records. AAAA or quad A
records resolve host names to IPv6 addresses,
where as A records resolve host names to IP
addresses. Pointer records (PTR) records do just
the opposite, they resolve IP addresses to fully
qualified domain names a reverse of A records.
CNAME records canonical name records
create aliases for host names,
this allows users to access a machine by
a potentially easier to understand name
rather than a possibly cryptic name for
the machine. And then we have MX records,
MX Mail Exchanger records are used to
indicate mail servers used in a network,
these and CNAME records must be entered
manually, an MX record has to entered
even after a mail server like Exchange is
installed. Start of authority (SOA) records
contain data for DNS zones, which are the parts
of a domain each DNS server is responsible for.